memoryexpress.com 2017-10-02

# Memory Express - Security & Privacy - Memory Express Inc.

At memoryexpress we know how important it is to protect your personal information. Whether you are shopping with us online or in person, we make every customer experience safe and secure. We have developed this Privacy Policy to outline our guidelines for the collection and use of personal information. At memoryexpress, we collect two types of information; personal information and non-personal information. 

### Personal Information

Personal information typically includes your name, address, phone number, and email address. You can always choose not to provide us with any of your personal information. However, if you make this choice, we may not be able to provide you with the product, service, or information that you requested. For example, we can only process online orders if you have provided us with certain financial information. With your consent we may use your personal information for a number of different purposes, for example to: 

  * Fulfill requests for products, services or information
  * Provide customer services
  * Administer contests or promotions
  * Offer new products and services
  * Measure and improve the effectiveness of our Web Sites or our marketing endeavors and in our online or in-store offerings to your preferences.

### Non-personal Information

Non-personal information does not identify you as an individual. For example, we may ask you for your postal code to assist us with planning our flyer distribution. 

We may also collect and summarize customer information in a format that no longer identifies the individual for statistical purposes. 

### Consent of Information Use

In some cases, your consent is implied if we ask you to provide personal information with a stated purpose. For example, we can only deliver the product you have purchased if you provide us with your address and phone number. 

In other cases, we will ask you to give your express consent to use your personal information to advise you of products or services that may be of interest. You always have the opportunity to "opt out" of having your information used for this purpose. 

If you have "opted in" or subscribed to one of our newsletters or mailing lists, we will always provide you the opportunity to "opt out" or unsubscribe. For example, each e-mail we send you will tell you how to decline further e-mail. 

### In-store purchases

When you purchase a memoryexpress product or service, you may need to provide us with contact and payment information (such as credit card information) so that we can process your request. Examples where we need contact information include delivery services, product servicing, in-home installations, warranty coverage, and rebate requests. If we collect this information, we will also ask for your consent to use this information to send you promotional information on products and services. 

### Rebates

Many of the products you purchase through memoryexpress are offered with rebates. To claim your rebate, you will usually be asked to provide your name, address, email address and proof of purchase. You may also be asked by either memoryexpress or the vendor to provide your consent to be added to promotional mailings and newsletters. Your consent is not a condition of receiving the rebate. 

### Contests, Promotion, and Survey

From time to time, we may run contests, promotions, or surveys. If you participate, you may be asked for contact information as well as additional optional survey information (for example, product preferences). Information from contest entries will be used to contact you if you win. We may also summarize survey information in a manner that no longer identifies the contest entrants for analysis, but will not share personal information from entries. All contests are subject to rules that will be available with each particular contest. 

### Our websites

While using our websites, you may be asked to voluntarily provide certain personal information (such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, or credit card information). We use this information to complete your transaction and to apply for access to certain special features and functions of the websites. If you choose not to provide requested personal information, you will not be able to use certain features of the websites and you will not be able to engage in transactions through the websites. 

With any of the services on our websites, we may also use your personal information to contact and correspond with you and to respond to your inquiries. With your consent, we may send to you, from time to time, email or other communications regarding goods or services we believe will interest you. 

### Information Collected Automatically

Like many other websites, we automatically collect certain non-personal information regarding website users that does not identify you. Examples include the Internet Protocol (IP) address of your computer, the IP address of your Internet Service Provider, the date and time you access the website, the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to the website, the operating system you are using, the sections of the website you visit, the website pages read and images viewed, and the content you download from the website. 

### Cookies

Our website uses "cookies", a technology that installs a small amount of information on a website user's computer to permit the website to recognize future visits using that computer. Cookies enhance the convenience and use of the website. For example, the information provided through cookies is used to recognize you as a previous user of the website (so you do not have to enter your billing information every time), to offer personalized web page content and information for your use, to track your activity at the website, to respond to your needs, and to otherwise facilitate your website experience. You may choose to decline cookies if your browser permits, but doing so may affect your use of the website and your ability to access certain features of the website or engage in transactions through the website. 

### Tracking information

We may use non-personal information to compile tracking information reports regarding website user demographics, website traffic patterns, and website purchases, and then provide those reports to advertisers and others. None of the tracking information in the reports can be connected to the identities or other personal information of individual users. We may also link tracking information with personal information voluntarily provided by website users. Once such a link is made, all of the linked information is treated as personal information and will be used and disclosed only in accordance with this Policy. 

### Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites or Internet resources. When you click on one of those links you are contacting another website or Internet resource. memoryexpress has no responsibility or liability for or control over those other websites or Internet resources or their collection, use and disclosure of your personal information. 

We encourage you to read the privacy policies of those other sites to learn how they collect and use information about you. 

### Disclosure of Information

memoryexpress does not sell your personal information. However, we may share your information with third parties acting on our behalf or as permitted or required by law. 

memoryexpress may share your personal information with certain service providers in order to provide products and services to you, to verify and validate information, and to address customer service matters. Examples of service providers include credit card issuers, product service depots, warranty providers, and delivery services. To reduce the risk of fraud or misuse of personal information, memoryexpress may also verify your personal information, including but not limited to your address and credit card information, with third party service providers. 

We will use reasonable efforts to ensure that your personal information is used in a manner that is consistent with this Policy. If you do not wish us to provide your personal information to those service providers, we may be unable to process your transaction. 

memoryexpress may disclose your information as permitted or required by law: 

  * To a government institution or other person or entity that has asserted its lawful authority to obtain the information
  * Where we have reasonable grounds to believe the information could be useful in the investigation of unlawful activity
  * To comply with a subpoena or warrant or an order made by a court, person or entity with jurisdiction to compel the production of information
  * To comply with court rules regarding the production of records and information
  * To our legal counsel

### How We Protect Your Information

The security of your personal information is a high priority for memoryexpress. We maintain appropriate safeguards and current security standards to protect your personal information, whether recorded on paper or captured electronically, against unauthorized access, disclosure, or misuse. 

Although we cannot take responsibility for any theft, misuse, unauthorized disclosure, loss, alteration or destruction of data by a third party, we take reasonable precautions to prevent such unfortunate occurrences. 

_Last Updated On June 15th, 2011_
